lgfcu.org 2004-06-24

# Privacy Policy

One of the most sacred qualities between a financial institution and the people who rely on it for services is trust.  Trust is one of the core principles of LGFCU. For this reason, we share with you our long-standing policies on a very important topic — privacy.

LGFCU has never, and will never, sell your financial information to anyone for any reason. Our policy has always been to keep your financial information private. This commitment is ongoing; and, before any new service is adopted at the Credit Union, we thoroughly review the scope of the service to make certain our privacy standards will be maintained.  If in the future, the Credit Union should identify a beneficial reason to share your personal financial information, your consent will be requested before any disclosure is made.

We have a special reason for protecting the privacy of members. The Credit Union is owned by its members and managed by a Board of Directors you elect. Because the Credit Union is a cooperative, you can be confident that your financial privacy is a top priority of this Credit Union. After all, the privacy of the board, volunteers, and staff of the Credit Union is at stake as well.

**Disclosing Financial Information**

LGFCU is committed to providing you with competitive products and services to meet your needs. In some cases, it is necessary that some information about you be shared with third party financial service providers that supply data processing and transactional services. The main provider of services to LGFCU is the State Employees' Credit Union (SECU).  LGFCU has a contractual agreement with SECU to provide member services and operational support. Law permits the disclosure of information about you in such an agreement. These disclosures typically include information to follow your instructions for service:

    * In order to complete transactions
    * To maintain your accounts
    * When you request additional services

To protect your privacy, all service providers to LGFCU must agree in writing to maintain strong confidentiality protections and not use information for any purpose other than specifically contracted. The Credit Union does not and will not permit service providers to sell to other third parties information about LGFCU members.

In the normal process of serving you, the Credit Union routinely collects nonpublic personal information about you from the following sources:

    * Information we receive from you on account and loan applications, such as name, address, social security number and income
    * Information about your transactions with others, or us such as account balances, payment history and credit card usage
    * Information we receive from a consumer-reporting agency, such as your creditworthiness and credit history
    * Information obtained when verifying the data you provide on an application, such as current and past employers, or other institutions where you conduct financial transactions.

Occassionally, LGFCU may be required by law to disclose nonpublic personal information for governmental or judicial purposes.

If you decide to terminate your membership or become an inactive member, we will adhere to the privacy policies and practices as described in this notice.

_How We Protect Your Information_

LGFCU is committed to maintaining a trustful relationship with our members by respecting and preserving our members' financial privacy. We require all employees to actively safeguard member privacy and confidentiality. We also have adopted physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards that comply with federal regulations and industry standards to protect your nonpublic personal information. If you have questions about the credit union's Privacy Policy, please contact us. We welcome your inquiries and comments.

Local Government Federal Credit Union  
Administrative Office  
801 Hillsborough Street, Suite 401  
Raleigh, North Carolina   27603

919.755.0534 (voice)  
800.344.4846 (toll free)  
919.755.0193 (fax)
